Joseph J. Fogarty

Website: josephfogarty.github.io Email: jf38@princeton.edu GitHub: github.com/josephfogarty

SUMMARY

Third-year graduate student enrolled in the department of Civil and Environmental Engineering (CEE) at Princeton University, conducting research in the Environmental Fluid Mechanics (EFM) research group. Although my undergraduate studies were in meteorology, my interests have changed from traditional operational forecasting to fluid dynamics and human-environment interactions. As a graduate student, my research interests lie in applying fluid mechanics to the intersection of humans and the environment; more specifically, employing numerical and observational tools to simulate the changing Arctic sea ice surface, ABL, and ocean.

EDUCATION

Princeton University

Princeton, NJ

Ph.D. in Environmental Engineering

2018-Current

- Advisor: Elie Bou-Zeid

Rutgers University

New Brunswick, NJ

2014-2018

B.S. in Meteorology, summa cum laude

- Advisor: Mark Miller

- Minors in Mathematics and Environmental Sciences

Research Experience

Nonlinearity of Air-Ice-Water Exchanges: Simulations of

Remotely-Sensed Surface States Poster Presentation at the Annual AGU Conference San Francisco, CA

2019

Modeling of Air-Sea-Ice Coupling of the Arctic Atmospheric Boundary Layer

Poster Presentation for CEE 509: Directed Research

Princeton, NJ 2019

Drizzle Evaporation in the Stratocumulus-Topped Marine Boundary Layer and its Relationship with Sub-Cloud Turbulence

Oral Presentation for George H. Cook Honors Project

New Brunswick, NJ

2018

Seasonal Trends in Extreme Minimum Temperatures at Six

New Jersey Locations Poster Presentation at Rutgers Climate Symposium Piscataway, NJ

2017

TEACHING

• Assistant in Instruction at Princeton University The Climatological, Hydrological, & Environmental Footprints of Cities (CEE 474) $Fall\ 2020$

• Assistant in Instruction at Princeton University

Fall 2019

Environmental Fluid Mechanics (CEE 305)

SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

Gordon S. Wu Scholarship
SEBS Dean's List
Meteorology Student of the Year
2018–2020
2014–2018

PROJECTS

More details of projects on github.com/josephfogarty

IceSUBS (Python, 2019)
Ice SUrface energy Budget Solver

Forecast Verification (Python/Jupyter, 2017)
Notebook to explore forecast verification techniques

Professional Experience

Office of the New Jersey State Climatologist

Piscataway, NJ 2017–2018

 $Under graduate\ Intern$

- Regular quality control for CoCoRaHS
- Synthesized national snow data for the 2016 Annual Snow Report
- Conducted independent research projects under the advice of the State Climatologist, including precipitation and extreme temperature analysis

Rutgers Environmental Sciences

New Brunswick, NJ

Weather Observer

2016-2018

- Conduct and record daily weather observations few days per week
- Organize other volunteers in the program by creating weekly schedules

Spot-On Weather
Undergraduate Intern

Marlboro, NJ
2016

- Handled operational forecasts for TV and film crews
 - Created forensic meteorology reports by using archival data for civil lawsuits

EXTRACURRICULAR

American Meteorology Society (AMS) Student Member

2017–Current 2019–Current

• American Geophysical Union (AGU) Student Member

2014 - 2018

Rutgers Meteorology Club
 Club Treasurer 2016–2017, Club President 2017–2018